爸
Dad...
你干什么
What are you doing?
你有三十秒时间来整装待发
You have 30 seconds to suit up.
我...
I--
游戏开始了
The game's afoot.
爸...
Dad--
别出声  让我享受这一刻
Wait. Let me savor this.
你十岁以后我就没赢过你
I haven't gotten the drop on you since you were 10.
而现在我嗅到了...
Oh, this feels like...
胜利的味道
Victory.
爸  我不能跟你玩
Dad, look, I can't, okay?
我还要做一个重大的决定呢
I have a big decision to make.
你至少已经缩小范围了吧
Well, have you at least narrowed it down?
我列出了所有学校的课程和课外活动
I made a list of all the classes and the extra curriculars.
最好的选择貌似就是
And the best choices seem to be
牛津和斯坦福了
Oxford and Stanford.
哥伦比亚大学  纽约大学和瓦萨尔学院呢
What about Columbia, N.Y.U., vassar?
那些都太近了
They're all too close.
我会一直往家跑的
I'd come home all the time.
我想挑战自我
I want to challenge myself,
不然我会沉迷在这种事情里的
and I'd get sucked in to things like this.
那以后谁来陪我玩
But then who's gonna play with me?
我觉得我该收起镭射枪
I think it's time to holster the laser guns
长大成人了
and be adults.
游戏结束
Game over.
请从出口离开
Please proceed to exit.
亲爱的  只是游戏而已
Oh, darling, it's just a game.
才不是
No, it's not.
这是历史悠久的家族传统
It's--it's a time-honored family tradition
从阿丽克西斯的小手
that we've been honoring since Alexis
能扣动扳机时就开始了
could wrap her little finger around a trigger.
从第一次到第一千分胜利
First one to 1,000 points wins,
差一点点就实现了
and we were so close.
我们...
We...
镭射枪伴随着她的整个童年
Laser tagged our way through her preteen years,
突然之间
and now suddenly,
她就...年纪大了  不玩了
she's... too old to play.
她长大了
She's growing up.
她不非得长大嘛  你瞧我
Well, she doesn't have to. Look at me.
看起来
Ah, well, it seems...
贝克特探长可以陪你玩
detective Beckett is available for a play date.
不是吧
Really?
我和贝克特最近
Beckett and I have not been exactly
相处得不是太好
hitting it off lately.
那你觉得是为什么
And why do you think that is?
不好意思  你是想说这是我的错吗
Oh, I-I'm sorry. Are you saying it's my fault?
跟糟糕的帮派警探胡闹
Cavorting with some awful gang detective,
带着空姐去犯罪现场
showing up at a crime scene with a stewardess--
如果你想惩罚贝克特
If you want to punish beckett,
至少要让她知道为什么
at least let her know why.
我没有在惩罚她
I'm not punishing her.
我...
I'm...
我有吗
Am I?
亲爱的  你受伤了  我明白
Oh, darling, you're hurt. I understand that.
但是说实在的  你们两个不能这样下去
But quite honestly, the two of you cannot go on like this.
妈  我跟你说
You know what, mother?
你说得对极了
You're absolutely right.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
犯罪现场
To a crime scene...
跟贝克特探长办最后一起案子
to work my last case with detective Beckett.
你说过你不喜欢咖啡的
You said you didn't like coffee.
可我喜欢香草拿铁
I like vanilla lattes.
-大家早  -早
- Hey, guys. - Hey.
谢谢你打电话给我
Thanks for calling.
不客气
Sure.
死者名叫大卫·洛克,  29岁
So our victim is David Lock, 29.
他在楼上的一家外币兑换处做货币交易员
He's a currency trader in a foreign exchange office upstairs.
看起来事发时他正要去工作
Looks like he was heading into work when it happened.
今早七点左右他的老板发现了他的尸体
His body was found by his boss at around 7:00 this morning.
我们无畏的英雄们到来了
Our intrepid heroes have arrived.
还有卡塞尔
And Castle.
帕穆特
Ah, Perlmutter.
我会珍视与你共度的美好时光
I will treasure these special moments we've shared.
我猜这个就是洛克先生了吧
So I take it that this is Mr. Lock?
看来他是被人袭击了
It appears he was set upon by an unknown assailant.
死亡时间大概是凌晨四点左右
Time of death was about 4:00 a.m.
死因呢
Cause of death?
可能是头部撞到混凝土地面
Well, probably blunt force trauma to the head
造成的钝器伤
where it hit the concrete.
值钱的东西都还在吗
Wallet and cash?
都还在  明显不是抢劫
Still intact, so it definitely wasn't a mugging.
凌晨四点的毒打  一定有什么动机
A savage beating at 4:00 a.m, there must be some motive.
他手上这是咬痕吗
Is this a bite mark on his arm?
不只是咬痕  看他的皮肤
It's not just a bite mark. Look at the skin.
都被撕烂了  看到没
You see how it's torn?
凶手像斗牛犬那样紧咬不放
The killer latched on and shook like a pit bull
试图把肉撕扯下来
trying to tear off the flesh.
谢谢你  我们懂了
Thanks. Think we got it.
还有什么发现
Anything else?
还有这个
Just this.
在被害人手里发现的
It was, uh, found in our victim's hand.
也许是挣扎的时候从凶手衣服上扯下来的
It was probably torn off the killer's shirt during the struggle.
这是个蕾丝袖口
That's a lace cuff.
手工缝制  珍珠纽扣
Hand stitched, pearl buttons--
应该是1870年左右的东西
I'd say this was circa 1870.
我在这方面做了不少研究
I did a lot of research on the era.
我之前在写一本关于内战的喜剧
I was writing a book, a comedy about the civil war.
结果貌似...不太喜感
Turns out... Not so funny.
是吗
You don't say?
谁会穿着150年前的衣服打死别人
Who would beat a guy to death wearing a 150-year-old shirt?
还有个更大的问题
You know, the bigger question is,
为什么他会在工作的地方遭到袭击
why was he attacked here where he worked?
你跟他老板谈谈吧
You might want to ask his boss--
麦克·马修
Mike Matthews.
真难以置信
I can't believe it.
我们认为大卫的死亡时间大概是凌晨四点
We think that David was killed around 4 a.m.
你知道他为什么来这么早吗
Do you have any idea why he was here so early?
大卫负责亚洲市场
David handled the asian markets,
所以一般都是四点过来
So he usually got in by 4:00.
他是个不错的孩子
He was a terrific kid.
工作努力  讨人喜欢
You know, he was hard-working, well-liked.
所有人都这么觉得吗
And was that the consensus?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  有任何同事和他有矛盾吗
I mean, did he have any conflicts with anyone at work?
事实上  上周发生了件事
Actually, yeah, there was an incident last week.
有人划了他的车
Someone keyed his car.
谁
Who?
大卫认为是查理·科尔曼
David thought it was Charlie Coleman,
另一个货币交易员
one of my other traders.
之前他俩都争取一个晋升的机会
Uh, the two of them were vying for a promotion,
而我选了大卫
and I went with David.
查理很不甘心
Charlie didn't take it too well.
查理一般几点来上班
What time does Charlie usually show up for work?
凌晨四点  和大卫一样
4 a.m., same time as David.
查理是...
Look, Charlie's...
有点古怪
kind of an oddball,
但我觉得他不会做这种事
but I-I don't see him mixed up in this.
不管怎样  我们都得找他谈
We're gonna need to talk to him anyway.
奇怪了
That's strange.
他的车就在大卫的车的旁边
His car is right there next to david's.
为什么这很奇怪呢
Why is that strange?
因为查理今天早上根本没来上班
Because Charlie never came into the office this morning.
他住在哪儿
What's his address?
太遗憾了
That's a shame.
本以为这案子会很有趣呢
This case had some real promise.
残忍的咬痕  重建时期的服装
Savage bite marks, reconstruction-era clothing--
本该是个有谜团有内情的案子
we had some mystery here, a whiff of intrigue.
可现在拷个心怀不满的员工结案了
Now we're just slapping cuffs on some disgruntled employee.
我就是希望这件案子会比较特别
I just wanted this one to be special.
很抱歉这案子提不起你的兴趣  卡塞尔
Yeah, well, I'm sorry it's not entertaining enough for you, Castle.
查理·科尔曼  纽约警局  开门
Charlie Coleman, NYPD. Open up.
别靠近  这里不安全
Stay away! It isn't safe!
退后
Stand back.
这是为了你们好
It's for your own good!
别进来  你们不能进来
Don't come in! You can't come in here!
很抱歉  查理
Sorry, Charlie.
查理  你没事吧  有人吗
Charlie, are you okay? Anyone here?
不不不不  退后
No, no, no, no. Get back!
离我远点
Get away from me!
我们只是想问你几个问题
Listen, we just gotta ask you a few questions.
你们得离开  现在就离开
You need to leave! You need to leave right now!
这里不安全
It's not safe!
放松  查理  放松  我们是警察
Relax, Charlie. Relax. We're cops.
-你是警察吗  -是的
- You're a cop? - Yeah.
那是你的枪吗
Is that your gun?
是的
Yeah.
开枪打我  快
You need to shoot me. Do it now!
开枪
Do it!
好了  查理  好点了吗
Okay, Charlie, you feeling better?
好些了
Uh, yeah.
我得问一下
Just gotta ask you a few questions
今早你和大卫之间发生的事情
about what happened this morning with you and David.
你在停车场看到他了吗
Did you see him in the parking structure?
是的  他刚刚进来
Yeah, he'd just pulled in.
我们相互问好
I said hello. He said hello.
其实我们关系不怎么好
The two of us aren't real friendly.
我们听说了  然后发生了什么
So we've heard. What happened next?
然后他停了下来
And then he stopped...
表情很奇怪地盯着我背后
and he stared right past me with this weird look on his face,
然后说  那是什么东西
and then he said, "What the hell is that?"
-那是什么呢  -一开始我没看清
- What the hell was it? - I couldn't tell at first,
因为它突然就扑向了我们
'cause suddenly, it was all over us.
等等  你也被袭击了吗
Wait. You were attacked, too?
是的  但它主要是攻击大卫
Yeah, but it was mostly after David.
它对着他哀嚎
I mean, it was just wailing on him.
我用手肘撞那东西的头  却根本没用
I elbowed it in the head, and it didn't even slow down.
你说"那东西"是什么意思
Okay, what do you mean by "it"?
我打911报警  他们不信我
I called 9-1-1. I told them. They didn't believe me.
没人相信我
No one believes me.
告诉我们你看到了什么
Just tell us what you saw.
你得保证你相信我
As long as you promise you'll believe me.
好的  我答应
Yeah, fine. I promise.
答应我
promise...
我一开始转化
that you will use your gun on me
就用你的枪杀了我
when I start to turn.
-转化  -是的
- Turn? - Yeah.
转化是什么意思
What do you mean, turn?
那个咬了我
The thing that bit me...
杀了大卫的东西
That killed David...
是僵尸
it was a zombie.
僵尸
A z-zombie?
是僵尸  是他妈僵尸
It was a zombie. A freakin' zombie!
先生  能再说一遍吗
Sir, can you repeat that?
僵尸  活死人  天啊  眼睛了无生气
A zombie. The undead. Oh, man...with those dead eyes
肿胀腐烂的皮肤从脸上脱落
and flaps of rotting skin coming off its face.
先生  这条线路仅用于紧急情况
Uh, sir, this line is for emergencies only.
你有什么紧急情况吗
Are you having an emergency?
有  重大紧急情况
Yes! I am having a major emergency here.
你不明白吗
Don't you get it?
这东西刚刚杀了一个人  还咬了我
This thing just killed someone, and it bit me!
我会变成僵尸的  下一个就是我
I'm gonna turn! I'm next.
这通报警电话是查理在受到袭击后打的
Now Charlie made this 9-1-1 call moments after the attack.
你觉得听起来像是假装的吗
Does it sound like he's faking to you?
听起来像是他精神崩溃了
It sounds like Charlie's having a psychotic break.
或许是内疚让他崩溃
What if his guilt made him snap
于是捏造了
and he created a fantasy
僵尸杀死大卫的幻想呢
in which zombies killed David and not him?
我不这么想
I'm not so sure.
他的声音听起来确实像是
I mean, his voice does have that authentic ring of
吓得要尿裤子了
pants-wetting terror.
你不是信了查理的故事吧
You do not believe in Charlie's story.
我相信他相信他的故事
I believe he believes it.
好吧  不管你相信什么
Okay, well, whatever you believe,
所有的证据都说明
all of the evidence points to the fact
查理·科尔曼是凶手
that Charlie Coleman is our killer.
也许不是所有的证据
Maybe not all the evidence.
鉴证组分析了查理手臂上的咬痕
C.S.U. analyzed that bite mark on Charlie's arm.
结果和死者身上的咬痕匹配
Turns out that it matches the bite mark on our victim.
也许查理咬了大卫之后又咬了自己
Maybe Charlie bit David and then he bit himself?
我也这么想  但是鉴证组还说
I was thinking the same thing, but C.S.U. also says
咬痕和查理的牙齿不匹配
that the bite marks weren't made by Charlie's teeth.
等等
Oh, wait, um...
不好意思
Sorry.
让我确定我听明白了
Let me make sure I understand
才能好好地享受这一刻
so that I might properly relish this moment.
你是说
You're saying...
证据显示查理和死者
The evidence shows that Charlie and the victim
都被不知是何方神圣的"第三人"咬了
both were bitten by an as-yet unknown third party.
-我就是这么说的  -也许这人是
- That's what I just said. - Perhaps even
不能思考的
a mindless...
脚步蹒跚的
shuffling...
活死人呢
undead third party.
卡塞尔  别说了
Castle, just stop.
世界上没有僵尸
There's no such thing as a zombie.
伙计们
Guys...
来看看这个
Uh, you gotta see this.
我在逐一查看停车场附近的
So I was combing through security camera footage
监控录像  然后发现了这个
near the parking garage, and I found this.
时间显示是凌晨四点过六分
Time stamp's 4:06 a.m.,
和死亡时间吻合
which fits time of death.
这是凶手
That's our guy.
是的  但这不是查理
Yeah, but that's not Charlie.
等等  他穿的是什么
Wait. What is he wearing?
看起来像是老式服装
That looks like an old-fashioned suit.
款式是1870年间而且...
Circa 1870 and...
他的衣服少了只袖子
his shirt's missing a cuff.
他差点被车撞了  却躲都没躲
He almost got hit by that taxi. He didn't even flinch.
估计原因在这里
Well, maybe this is why.
瞧瞧另一个角度拍下的画面
Look what we get from the other angle.
伙计们
My friends...
这玩意儿
that...
是个僵尸
is a zombie.
凶手是僵尸
Our killer's a zombie.
你还挺开心的嘛  考虑到你放话说
Well, you're rather upbeat considering you said
这是你跟贝克特的最后一起案子
this was your last case with Beckett.
那是因为我要华丽地离开
That's because I am going out with a bang.
可以用一个词形容  老妈
I have one word for you, mother...
僵尸
Zombie.
因为我妆化多了吗
Too much makeup?
你看起来很好  我是说被害人
You look lovely. I'm referring to our victim
是被一具行尸走肉杀害的
being killed by one of the walking undead.
说真的  就是僵尸
And I mean that literally-- a zombie.
监控录像把他那副腐烂的样子都拍下来了
Security camera caught him in all his putrefying glory.
你该不会下载了这段录像吧
I don't suppose you downloaded this video by chance?
当然没有  那是警方证物
Absolutely not. That video's police property.
我要是截了屏
It would be very, very wrong of me to...
还发到我邮箱里  就大大的不对了
get a screen grab of it and e-mail it to myself.
那就让它成为我们之间的小秘密吧  亲爱的
Ooh. Well, it'll be our little secret, darling.
老妈  你怎么会对这个案子这么好奇
I'm actually surprised at your interest in this case, mother.
我能看出
Well, I really do know the difference
一流的妆容和真正的腐肉之间的区别
between a first-rate makeup job and actual decay.
你要是想看真正的僵尸
You want to see some real zombies,
去看托尼奖红地毯上那些个人就好了
check out the red carpet at the Tony Awards.
我不是...
I thought I...
我不是把这个放起来了吗
I thought I put this away.
她在哪
Where is she?
被我昨天的演技蒙蔽了吧
You were a fool to buy my act yesterday.
这会儿你正中我的陷阱
And now you've fallen right into my trap.
你会为你的背叛付出惨痛代价的
You will pay dearly for your treachery.
还有你  老妈  居然把我引到这来
Et tu, mother, for luring me here.
怎么了  我听不懂你的意思
Why, whatever do you mean?
不亏是我的宝贝女儿
That's my girl.
那个僵尸是怎么回事
So what's this about a zombie?
我的苍天呐
Oh, my god.
早告诉你们了  就是他
I told you people. That's him.
好脏好邪恶
Oh, so vile and disgusting--
这就是我看到的僵尸
That's the zombie that I saw.
我们并不能肯定他是个
Well, we're not exactly sure that he's a--
什么叫你们不确定
What do you mean, you're not sure?
不然他还能是什么东西
What else could he be?
重点在于  你的嫌疑被洗清了
The point is, this puts you in the clear.
你可以走了
We're releasing you.
这可不是什么好主意
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
查理  你如果要转化
Charlie, if you were going to turn,
这会儿肯定已经转了
you would have done it by now.
这玩意儿  你们抓到了吗
This thing, have you caught it?
还没  放心  我们会抓住他的
Not yet. Rest assured, we will.
我要待在这儿
I'll just stay here.
他不肯走
He won't leave?
查理对这个僵尸的事情深信不疑
Charlie's pretty convinced about this whole zombie thing.
这也太荒谬了吧
Yeah, but that's just-- that's ridiculous.
是吗
Or is it?
到目前  查理都说对了
Charlie has not been wrong yet.
或许凶手就是第一感染源
Maybe our killer is Patient Zero,
现在正在纽约大街上到处咬人
out there right now on the streets of New York,
建立一支活死人大军呢
building an army of the undead.
卡塞尔  我们要找的不是僵尸
Castle, what we are looking for is not a zombie,
而是一个狡猾的罪犯  他杀了大卫·洛克
but a very smart criminal who murdered David Lock
还把唯一的目击证人变得疯疯癫癫
and is now making our only witness look crazy,
他为了隐藏身份
and he also dressed up
给自己化了妆  穿上戏服
in makeup and a costume to hide his identity.
除非这不是化妆  也不是戏服
Unless that's not a costume or makeup.
他看起来确实像是真僵尸
I mean, he does look like a real zombie.
真僵尸
A real zombie?
真替你臊得慌  兄弟
I'm embarrassed for you, bro.
好吧  那你来解释
Okay, then explain this--
一个僵尸怎么会
why would a zombie go after
凌晨四点在停车场里攻击一名外币交易员
a currency trader at 4:00 a.m. in a garage?
这个简单
This one's easy.
人的智商越高
The more intelligent the victim,
其大脑就越美味
the more delicious the brains.
回到现实世界
So returning to the land of facts,
-彻查犯罪现场有什么结果吗  -没有
- what did you find at the crime scene canvass? - Nada.
一个人装成僵尸在街上走  居然没人发现
Only in New York could some guy dress like a friggin' zombie
只有纽约才会发生这种事
and walk down the street unnoticed.
我倒是发现案发前死者行踪有一段空白
Oh, I did find a gap in our timeline before the murder.
什么意思
What do you mean?
根据门卫的口供
Well, according to the doorman, the victim
死者于凌晨两点离开公寓  再没回去过
left his apartment at 2:00 a.m. and he never came back.
他于凌晨四点被害  这中间的两小时他在干嘛
He was killed at 4:00 a.m.. What was he doing for 2 hours?
不知道  不过他开车去的
I don't know, but he drove there.
信用卡消费记录显示2点44分
His credit card showed that
他在休斯顿加过油
he gassed up on Houston at 2:44 a.m.
我们去查他去了哪里
All right. Let's figure out where he went.
凶手可能是跟踪他到停车场的
Trouble might have followed him to the garage.
或许是个僵尸
Or a zombie did.
我来告诉你们他去了哪
I'll tell you where he went.
找炮友去了
Booty call.
技术部的同事在大卫的手机上找到一条短信
Tech guys pulled a text message off David's phone.
是他在被害当晚发给一个
He sent it to a chica the night he died
姑娘的求爱短信
wanting to hook up with her.
能查到对方名字吗
Does she have a name?
格蕾塔·马斯特亚尼
Greta Mastroianni.
我不明白
Look, I-- I don't understand.
谁会对大卫下这样的杀手
Who would do something like this to David?
那晚你有没有见过他
Did you see him that night?
我们知道他给你发短信想跟你见面
We know that he texted you wanting to come over.
我们没见面  我打电话叫他别来了
No, I-I called him and told him not to.
一周前我跟大卫分手了
I split up with David about a week ago.
可他还不肯死心
Um, he was still trying to hold on.
你们为什么分手
Why'd you two split up?
我订婚了  呃...
I'm engaged, um...
跟汤姆  汤姆·威廉姆斯
To Tom-- Tom Williams.
我们在一起五年了
We've been together five years.
那你跟大卫是怎么回事
How did David figure in?
我21岁那年在洛杉矶
I met him when I was 21,
探亲的时候认识了他
visiting a cousin in L.A.
我们度过了几周很愉快的日子
We had an intense couple of weeks, you know,
然后三个月前  我在咖啡店又碰到了他
then three months ago, I ran into him at a coffee shop.
你未婚夫知道你和大卫的事吗
And did your fiance know about this affair with David?
知道  他上周看到了我电脑里的邮件
Yeah, he found, uh, e-mails on my computer last week.
他有什么反应
And how did he react to that?
很受伤  威胁说要离开我
He was hurt, he threatened to leave me,
那时我才意识到我不能没有他
and that's when I realized what I was about to lose,
因此跟大卫分了手
so I broke it off with David
乞求汤姆再给我一次机会
and begged Tom to give me another chance.
他原谅了我
And he did.
汤姆昨晚在哪
So where was Tom that night?
在家  我们十一点左右睡的
Home. We went to bed around 11:00.
他整晚都在吗
And he was there all night?
格蕾塔...凌晨四点时汤姆在哪
Greta... Where was Tom at 4:00 a.m.?
我不知道
Look, I don't know, okay?
我两点半的时候醒过来  他不在身旁
I woke up around 2:30, and he wasn't there.
我以为他在客厅里看电视
I figured he was watching TV in the living room,
但我早上起床的时候  发现...
but when I got up in the morning--
他不在公寓里  那他一整晚去哪了
He wasn't in the apartment. So where was he all night?
我知道你想说什么
I see what you're getting at with this, okay?
但是这事跟汤姆没关系
But Tom had nothing to do with it.
大卫是用公司的邮件给你发的电邮吗
Did David e-mail you from his office account?
是
Yeah.
怎么了
Why?
这样一来你未婚夫就知道大卫在哪工作
Because that means that your fiance knew where David worked.
那家伙死了我并不难过
Look, I can't say I feel bad this guy is dead.
但他的死跟我无关
But I had nothing to do with it.
尽管他想抢你的未婚妻
Even though he was trying to snake your fiancee?
他根本不是个问题
He was out of the picture.
格蕾塔已经做出了选择  她选了我
Greta made her choice, and she picked me.
是啊  可惜他不肯罢休
Yeah, except he wouldn't take no for an answer.
我敢说  你肯定发现了他给她发短信的事
You know, I bet you found out that he was texting her,
于是决定让他没法再这么干
and you decided to make him stop texting her
永消后患
permanently.
你想错了
Well... You're wrong.
我没碰过他  我都没见过他
I never touched the dude. I never even met him.
但这事肯定让你很生气
Yeah, but it had to have made you angry.
我说实话
I-I won't lie to you.
这事确实很难接受
This whole thing has been tough.
但是我和格蕾塔要共度余生
But Greta and I are building a life together,
我认为经历了这事  我们会更坚强
and I think we're gonna come out of it stronger--
汤姆  你大约多高
Tom, about how tall are you?
有一米八吗
About 6'?
一米八六
6'2".
那么跟这个人差不多高吧
So about the same height as this guy, right?
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that?
别傻了  那不是我啊
Come on. That's not me.
你那晚离开了公寓
When you left the apartment that night,
接下来的一个半小时去了哪
where were you for the next hour and a half?
大卫也是在这个时段不明踪迹
David was missing for the same amount of time--
凌晨两点半到四点
2:30 to 4:00 a.m.
在哈德逊法律图书馆自习
A-at the Hudson Law Library studying.
你那个时间去图书馆
You were at the library at that hour?
期末期间全天候开放
It's open 24/7 during finals.
你可以去问问图书馆员和其他十个
You can ask the librarian and the ten other people
在那儿自习的人
who were studying there.
我会的
I will.
汤姆的话得到证实了
Tom's alibi checks out.
他上午三点到六点都在法律图书馆
He was at the Law Library between 3:00 and 6:00 a.m.
我真以为他就是凶手
I really thought that he was our man.
大卫·洛克又没有其他的仇家
And it's not like David Lock has any other enemies.
这点我们已经跟他的朋友和同事证实了
I mean, we already confirmed that with his friends and coworkers.
那刚刚去世的朋友和同事呢
What about recently deceased friends and coworkers?
好吧  不管是谁或者什么
Okay. Well, whatever or whoever this is,
我们能不能至少认同  他看着像僵尸
can we at least agree that he looks like a zombie,
穿的像僵尸  行为像僵尸
he dresses like a zombie, and he acts like a zombie?
这对我们有什么帮助
And that helps us how?
我们现在寻找的是正常的动机
We're looking at standard motives here.
但驱使这个凶手的不是复仇  贪婪或权利
But our killer isn't driven by revenge, greed, or power,
如果他把自己当做僵尸就不会如此
not if he thinks he's a zombie.
要是这么想
So then by that line of thinking,
他的动机是杀人的原始冲动
his motive is a primal urge to kill?
他不管杀的是谁  只想大开杀戒
Regardless of who the victim is, he kills at random.
没错
Precisely.
那你说说我们在八百万人口的城市里
Then how do you propose that we find a random killer
要怎么找一个肆意杀人的凶手
in a city of eight million people?
或许可以
Maybe we start
从死者失踪期间去了哪查起
with where the victim went during those missing two hours.
快说
Do tell.
实验室分析出了大卫·洛克鞋底
Well, the lab I.D.'ed a chemical found recently deposited
新沾上的化学物质
under the bottom of David Lock's shoes.
什么样的化学物质
What kind of chemical?
太不好读了
Uh, I won't even begin to try to pronounce it,
但是纽约和新泽西的三家工厂有用到
but it is used in three factories in New York and New Jersey.
大卫被杀当晚
The night that David was killed,
他去了休斯顿的一家加油站
he went to a gas station on Houston.
这里哪个工厂离那儿近
Which one of those factories is closest to Houston?
下东区的那一家
The one on the Lower East Side,
但是已经闭厂一年了
but it's been closed for over a year.
我们走
Let's go.
我们现在能够确定这里确实是废弃了
Well, we know now this is, in fact, an abandoned factory...
就坐落在一个落寞  凄凉的小巷里
in a desolate, godforsaken alley.
又开始胡思乱想了吧  卡塞尔
Imagination getting the better of you, Castle?
没有啊  没有
No, no. Of course not.
只是希望没这么大老远白跑一趟
Just wish we had more to show for our efforts. That's all.
我不能理解的是
The thing that I don't get is,
大卫·洛克那样的货币交易员干嘛跑到这儿来
why would a currency trader like David Lock come down here?
真是完全说不通
It just doesn't make any sense.
除非他有我们不了解的阴暗面
Unless he had a dark side we know nothing about.
比如
Like what?
我只知道正常人
All I know is that normal people
是不会凌晨两点跑来这种地方
don't come to places like this at 2:00 a.m. in the morning.
说实话  我想走了  你呢
In fact, I think I've seen enough. Haven't you?
等等  你听到了吗
Wait. Do you hear that?
我才不会被骗呢
I'm not falling for that.
不是闹着玩的  你听
No, no, no, I'm serious. Listen.
-脚步声  -是啊
- Footsteps. - Yeah.
而且有很多人
Lots of 'em.
老天啊
Oh, my god!
他们在追我们  他们在追我们
They're after us! They're after us!
谁啊
Who is?
你们干嘛呢  别傻站着  跑啊
What are you people doing? Don't just stand there! Run!
快走
Come on!
怎么回事啊
What the hell is going on?
那是  那是一群僵尸啊
That's--that's a zombie-- that's a zombie horde.
才没有什么僵尸呢
There's no such thing as zombies.
不用提醒你照头爆吧
I'm sure I don't have to tell you to aim for the head.
贝克特  后面也有  我们被包围了
Beckett, they're behind us. We're surrounded.
老天啊
Oh, jeez. Oh, jeez.
你的子弹可不够
You don't have enough bullets.
这里就是僵尸世界大战的地零点了
It's ground zero for world war z.
躲到我身后
Get behind me.
我们得杀出一条血路
We'll have to fight our way out.
这太糟糕了
This is so not cool.
这绝对不是真的
There's no way this is real.
纽约警局
NYPD!
立刻停下来
Stop moving now.
不要再扮僵尸了
And stop pretending to be zombies.
别激动啊
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
我们就是在玩行尸走肉
We're just zombie walking here.
你们什么
You're what?
行尸走肉
Z-zombie walking.
类似于扮装抓人游戏
It's like an amped up form of tag.
我们扮成僵尸  去追正常人
We--we dress up like zombies, and we chase the normals.
我们就是正常人
That would be us.
我们抓到他们就可以转化他们
Yeah, yeah, if we tag 'em, we turn 'em,
那他们就也变成僵尸了
and then they become zombies, too.
如果你们这是为了我们没有许可证的事
Look, if this is because we didn't get a permit, I--
不是
It's not!
你们都要马上跟我回警局去
You're all coming with me. Now.
怎么没人告诉我这件事
how did I not know about this?!
好逼真  是你自己做的吗
This is outstanding. Did you do this yourself?
做为僵尸脑残粉  我懂
Being a fan of zombie lore, I get it.
真正做僵尸有什么意思啊
But what's the appeal of being a zombie?
看看这个人
Like look at this guy.
谁会想在腐烂无意识的状态下活着
Who would want to be alive in a decayed, mindless state?
做个吸血鬼  我能理解
Being a vampire-- that I understand.
那是走向不死的浪漫意淫之旅
That's the romantic route to immortality.
可以说是有品位的怪物
The, uh, gentlemen's monster, as it were.
说到怪物
Speaking of monsters,
这里的僵尸没有跟凶手照片匹配的
none of these zombies match the photo of our killer.
或许他在尝试新造型
Maybe he's trying out a new look.
你呢
How about you?
如果你能成为超自然生物  想做什么
If you could be any supernatural creature, what would it be?
范海辛  毫无疑问
Van Helsing. No question.
怪物杀手  很合适
Monster slayer. Befitting.
想象一下
And imagine,
我们正追捕的这个怪物
the monster that we are hunting
可能就在这屋里
might be in this very room.
姑娘们  感谢你们的配合
All right, ladies, thanks for your help.
搞不懂那双鞋为什么配那件上衣
I don't know about those shoes with that top.
我是说我会选露趾鞋
I'm just sayin'. I'd have went open-toed.
你们比我们进展顺利吗
Are you guys having more luck than we are?
丝毫没进展
Not at all.
还有
Oh, and guess what.
这些傻蛋里没一个是真僵尸
None of these knuckleheads are real zombies.
我认为我同事的意思是
I think what my colleague means to say is
没人认得出视频上的僵尸
that no one recognized our zombie from the video
和死者大卫·洛克
or our victim David Lock.
如果大卫不是僵尸群里的一员
If David wasn't a part of the zombie crowd,
那他在那里干什么
then what was he doing down there?
他肯定不是我们的成员
He definitely wasn't part of our group,
我敢确定
I can tell you that.
你呢  你认识他吗
What about you? Do you recognize him?
什么
What?
保罗  你是不是嗑药了
Paul, are you high right now?
没有  没有
Whoa. Whoa. Hey now.
你怎么会...
Uh... Where's that...
这么想
coming from?
没  没  当然没
No. No, of course not.
喂
Hello.
对
Right. Um...
我不认识这家伙
Yeah, yeah, I-I don't know this dude.
他不是僵尸  也不是普通人
He's not a-a zombie or a-a normal.
听着
Listen,
还要很久吗
will this take much longer?
我早上还得上课
I have a class in the morning.
-你是学生吗  -我是老师
- You're a student? - A teacher.
是吗
Really?
人类学的助理教授
Assistant professor of anthropology.
我认为我们对僵尸的迷恋
I believe our fascination with zombies
是一种文化现象
is a cultural phenomenon,
对现代生活内心麻痹的一种映射
a commentary on the inner numbness of modern life.
好
Yeah, okay.
你们谁认得这个
Do either of you recognize this,
僵尸
uh, zombie?
那是凯尔
That's Kyle.
凯尔·詹宁斯
Kyle Jennings.
纽约警局  凯尔·詹宁斯
NYPD! Kyle Jennings!
是他吗
Is that him?
对  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
凯尔
Kyle.
他死了
He's dead.
那死因我们知道吗
So do we have cause of death?
你说"我们"  其实指的是我
I assume by "We," you mean me.
等我解剖后才能知道
I'll have answers after I cut him open.
人真好
Charming.
我们都是臭脾气  卡塞尔  习惯就好
We're all meat, Castle. Get over it.
我现在能得出的结论是  他的牙和咬痕能对上
What I can tell you is, his teeth match the bite marks,
而且他衣服上的血迹是死者的
and the blood on his clothes came from the victim.
凯尔·詹宁斯就是凶手
Kyle Jennings is your killer.
问题是  谁杀了他
Well, the question is, who killed him?
那不一直都是问题吗
Isn't that always the question?
只是...
Uh, you know, just--
干什么  卡塞尔
What is it, Castle?
不  我只是想知道
No, I was just wondering,
他死前  他的举止跟僵尸一样
before this man died, he was behaving exactly like a zombie.
有没有医学的方法可以确定
Is there any medical way to determine...
他是不是真的是...
if he actually was...
僵尸
one?
他怎么会出现在我的停尸室
W-w-why is he in my morgue?
卡塞尔  僵尸是不存在的
There are no zombies, Castle.
他只是个男人  之前活着
This is a man. He was a live man.
现在死了
Now he's a dead man.
故事结束
End of story.
他是活死人
It's undead!
卡塞尔  叫支援
Castle, call for backup!
怎么...
How--how do I--
播9
9. 9.
9.
有没有在逃僵尸的警用代码
Is there a police code for zombie on the loose?
根据急诊室的最新报告
So based on the latest report from the E.R.,
凯尔·詹宁斯被转到重症监护室了
Kyle Jennings was transferred up to I.C.U.
他情况稳定了  但镇定剂药性还没过
He is stable but under sedation.
我跟你说  这个人已经死了
I'm telling you, that guy was dead.
记得提醒我别在你面前被鸡骨头卡住喉咙
Remind me never to choke on a chicken bone in front of you.
你也检查过他的脉搏  医护人员也查了
Hey, you checked that guy. So did the paramedics.
别吵  我相信
Whoa. You guys, I'm sure
肯定会有合理的医学解释的
that there's a medical explanation for it.
解释倒是有
Oh, there's an explanation, all right.
除了那个
Besides that one.
你也在那里  你也看见了
Come on. You were there. You saw it.
他死而复生了
He rose from the dead.
他不是死而复生  卡塞尔
He didn't rise from the dead, Castle.
他本来就没死
He wasn't dead in the first place.
没错  他不是僵尸  卡塞尔
Yeah, he's not a zombie, Castle.
他只是个谋杀犯
He's just a murderer.
那他的动机是什么
Well, then what was his motive for murder,
埃斯波西托警探
Detective Esposito?
凯尔是卖保险的
Kyle sold insurance.
没有前科
He had no criminal record.
没有证据显示他认识死者
There's no evidence he even knew our victim.
他是个有着人类动机的人类杀手
He's a human killer with a human motive.
也可能是个有着僵尸动机的僵尸杀手
Or he's a zombie killer with a zombie motive.
美味的脑子
Tasty brains.
卡塞尔  你真的相信
You know, Castle, do you really believe
僵尸的说法吗  因为
in all this zombie stuff, because I--
我以我死去奶奶的名义发誓凯尔·詹宁斯死了
I would swear on my nana's grave that Kyle Jennings was dead.
不
No.
你知道我相信什么吗
You know what I do believe in?
把贝克特逼疯
Driving Beckett crazy.
我不得不说  很高兴看到你们俩
I have to say, it's good to see you guys
再次和好
hitting it off again.
卡塞尔  看来我们能从当事人那
Well, Castle, looks like we will get our motive
直接问出动机了
straight from the source.
凯尔·詹宁斯先生已经醒了
Mr. Kyle Jennings is officially awake.
凯尔  我是贝克特警探  这是卡塞尔先生
Kyle, I'm detective Beckett. This is Mr. Castle.
我怎么会在医院  为什么有警察守在外面
What am I doing here? Why are there cops outside?
没人告诉我这是怎么回事
No one's telling me anything.
是我被打劫了还是怎么
What, was I mugged or something?
我们要问你几个关于大卫·洛克的问题
We need to ask you a few questions about David Lock.
-谁  -照片上这人
- Who? - This man.
我不认识他
I don't know him.
两天前  他也参加了行尸走肉
Two nights ago, he went on a zombie walk.
你们在那见过吗
Did the two of you meet there?
我不是说了吗  从来没见过这人
I'm telling you, I've never seen the guy before.
到底是怎么回事
What is this about?
他被谋杀了
He was murdered.
活活被打死的
Beaten to death.
行尸走肉时到底发生了什么
What happened at that zombie walk?
记不得了
I can't remember.
你能记得的最后一件事是什么
Well, what's the last thing you do remember?
我弄好装扮去参加活动
Uh, I... got dressed to head over there.
然后就在停尸房醒来了
The next thing I know, I woke up in the morgue.
你那晚喝酒或者嗑药了吗
Did you drink or do drugs that night?
我不喝酒不嗑药的
I don't do that stuff. Look...
我没有伤害任何人  真的
I didn't hurt anyone, okay?
我不会干那种事的
I would never do that.
我只是什么都记不得了
I just-- I don't remember anything.
你衣服上有被害人的血
Well, the victim's blood was found on your clothes,
咬痕和你的牙齿也吻合
Bite marks match your teeth,
他手里还攥着你衬衫的袖口
The cuff of your shirt was clutched in his hand,
还有监控录像拍到了凶手的样子
And a security camera caught our killer on tape.
这是你吗  凯尔
Is that you, Kyle?
是
Yes.
是我没错
That's me.
我看你得请个律师了
I think you're gonna need a lawyer.
凯尔无缘无故杀了一个他没见过的人
So Kyle killed someone he never met for no reason.
难道我们要相信这样的结果吗
Is that what we're supposed to believe?
你不是说僵尸就是这样吗
Well, isn't that what you said zombies do?
很伤心地说
It is with a sad heart, I say that
那人不是僵尸
That man is no zombie.
就算他死而复生也不是吗
Oh, even though he rose from the dead?
是人都知道  变成僵尸之后
It's common knowledge, when you turn into a zombie,
没法再变回来
you cannot turn back.
所以你同意
So you concede to the fact that
这些事都能用医学来解释咯
there's a medical explanation to all of this?
我什么都没认
I concede to nothing
但我肯定凯尔还有所隐瞒
except that Kyle is not telling us the whole story.
你认为他记得
You think he remembers?
这种改变人生的事件但凡发生
When a life-altering moment occurs,
人都会记得
people remember.
也许是因为太重大  一时处理不来
Well, maybe it's too big to deal with.
也许他
Maybe he...
现在还没法面对
can't face it just yet.
你觉得他以后能吗
Well, you think he ever will be?
希望如此
Hopefully,
前提是他觉得安全
if he feels safe.
帕穆特
Perlmutter?
你在这干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
我来照顾我的病人  凯尔·詹宁斯
I came to tend to one of my patients--Kyle Jennings.
你觉得这是个好主意吗
Do you think that's a good idea?
不怕告诉你  我治活人
I'll have you know, I'm perfectly capable
一样拿手
of treating living patients.
我只是不乐意
I simply prefer not to.
这次例外
I made an exception here
是因为他的血液检测结果很不寻常
because the results of his blood work are quite unusual.
什么意思
What do you mean?
凯尔·詹宁斯身体里有莨菪碱
Kyle Jennings had scopolamine in his system,
小剂量的莨菪碱可以用来治晕动症
which, in small doses, is used to treat motion sickness.
剂量大的话  能影响中枢神经
In larger doses, it acts on the central nervous system
使人的行为极易服从控制和影响
to promote compliant and suggestible behavior.
有多容易被影响
Exactly how suggestible?
基本上让你干啥就干啥
You'll basically do whatever you're told.
就像迷奸药一样
It's like a date-rape drug,
不过被害人意识清醒
only the victim remains conscious.
药效一过
And when the drug wears off,
被害人就什么都不记得了
you have no recollection of what happened.
有没有可能有人给凯尔下药了
Is it possible somebody slipped Kyle that drug?
我觉得很有可能
I think it's highly probable that they did.
他是什么时候服了莨菪碱的
What time do you think he was given the scopolamine?
凶案当晚2点45到3点45之间
Between 2:45 and 3:45 the night of the murder.
正好是参加行尸走肉的时候
That's when he was on that zombie walk.
行尸走肉队伍里面有人对他下药
Someone on the zombie walk drugged Kyle
让他去杀大卫
and sent him after David.
凯尔是无辜的
Kyle's innocent.
这案子根本就不是随机的僵尸伤人
Far from a random active zombie mayhem,
而是深思熟虑的蓄意谋杀
this murder was fiendishly deliberate.
谋划的天衣无缝
It was meticulously planned...
此人有强烈动机
By someone with a powerful motive...
还得能弄到那种药
With access to those drugs...
同时参加了行尸走肉
Who was also at our zombie walk.
但我们已经讯问过那些人了
But we interviewed those people.
没有任何证据表明大卫认识他们
There's no evidence that David knew any of them
又或者和僵尸事件有关
or had anything to do with the zombie scene.
我们知道他下去了
Well, we know he was down there.
总得有个原因吧
He had to have gone there for a reason.
最好还是追查下药这条线
Maybe our best bet is to work this through the drug angle.
已经在做了
Uh, I got started on that,
我做了一些关于莨菪碱的调查
and I did some research on scopolamine.
-好样的  -副作用一大串
- Nice. - Quite the list of side effects,
包括犯困  混乱  口齿不清
including drowsiness, confusion, slurred speech,
还有死亡
death.
道上能弄到这种药吗
Is it available on the street?
不常见  但是能弄到  还有
It's uncommon, but it's out there, and get this--
这种药被叫做"僵尸药"
users refer to it as "The zombie drug."
我刚好认识一个能为我们答疑解惑的僵尸
And I know just the zombie to tell us all about it.
又怎么了  我回答过你们的问话了
Hey, what is this? I answered all your guys' questions.
你上次来的时候  服了什么
When you were here last time, what were you on?
服了
On?
你  什么意思
What do you-- what do you mean?
保罗  你明显嗑药了
You were under the influence, Paul.
嗑得都找不到北了
Heavily under the influence.
是莨菪碱吗
Was it scopolamine?
什么东西
Whoa. What now?
你是不是用了僵尸药
Do you use the zombie drug?
这个
I suppose that's...
有可能
possible.
其它僵尸也用吗
Do any of the other zombies use it?
有些用
Some do.
有人说那能让僵尸体验更过瘾
Some say it enhances the zombie experience.
你从哪弄到的
Where did you get it?
有人卖啊
A guy down there sells the stuff.
谁  叫什么
Who? What's his name?
不知道  又没问过
I don't know. I never asked.
描述一下长相
Well, describe him.
黑头发  挺高的  1米8多
Dark hair, tall, over 6'.
是他吗
Is this him?
没错  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
感谢你再次赶来  汤姆
Thanks for coming in again, Tom.
没事  虽然我不知道自己能帮上什么忙
Sure. Though I'm not sure what I can do.
我听说你们抓到凶手了
I heard you caught the guy.
嗯  但我们还需要你帮忙
Yeah, well, we just needed you to help us
将些许零星的碎片拼起来
tie up a few loose ends.
这就是我们的嫌疑犯凯尔·詹宁斯
So this is our suspect-- Kyle Jennings.
我记得你上次问过了
Yeah, I remember from last time.
你说你从没见过他
Now you said that you've never seen him before.
他挺难让人忘记的  不是吗
Well... he'd be hard to miss, right?
那真是太有趣了  因为凯尔说他看见你了
Yeah, that's funny, 'cause Kyle said he saw you.
对  他说你也参与了行尸走肉
Yeah, he says you were at the zombie walk.
你从没告诉我们  你是僵尸亚文化的一份子
You never told us that you were a part of the zombie subculture.
警探  我在读法律预科
Detective, I'm pre-law.
我可没时间专研文化
I-I have no time for regular culture,
更别说是亚文化了
let alone subculture.
汤姆  你太谦虚了
Oh, Tom, you're too modest.
很多僵尸都称赞你
A number of zombies sang your praises.
显然  你就是为僵尸体验提供
Yeah, apparently, you're the go-to guy
莨菪碱的首选人物
for the real zombie experience with the scopolamine.
什么
The what?
你在伍德市出生
You're a kid from Ridgewood, Tom.
你没工作
You don't even have a job.
但却住在很高档的公寓里
And yet, you manage to afford a really nice apartment
并有能力支付学费
and you're able to pay your tuition.
我申请了学生贷款
I-I took out student loans.
听着
Look...
我真不是毒贩
I'm--I'm--I'm not a drug dealer.
你想出人头地
You're trying to get ahead.
和格蕾塔一起生活
You know, make a life with Greta.
可她却和某个华尔街的混蛋搭上了
And then she steps out with some Wall Street douche
那人不肯跟她分手
who just would not let her go.
大卫在他死的那晚想见见格蕾塔
David wanted to see Greta the night that he was killed.
可她拒绝了
She said no.
我们调查了那区
We canvassed the area.
有人看见他坐在车内  在你家外苦苦守候
He was seen sitting in his car outside of your apartment.
那晚你离开后
When you left that night,
他跟踪你到行尸走肉
he followed you to the zombie walk.
我打赌他跟你说他要争取格蕾塔
I'm betting he told you he was gonna fight for Greta.
他高富帅
He was handsome, he had money,
而且两人交往过
the two of them had a history.
你知道自己不是他对手
I mean, you knew you couldn't compete.
要是大卫告诉格蕾塔
Yeah, especially if David told Greta
你不过是个低劣的毒贩  就更没戏了
you're nothing but a low-life drug dealer.
你只能自己解决麻烦
You had to take matters into your own hands.
或者更具体  借凯尔的手
Or more specifically, Kyle's hands.
你想了个妙计
So you had this brilliant plan.
你给凯尔服用莨菪碱
You dosed Kyle with scopolamine,
告诉他杀死大卫
told him to kill David.
这样  人不知鬼不觉
Thinking, nobody will ever figure it out.
但事实上  最后一点没像计划的那样如意
Actually, that last part didn't work out so well.
对
Yeah.
你们手上
All you have
只有一些精神失常的僵尸的证词
is the word of a few whacked out zombies.
那不足以成为合理依据
That's not even close to probable cause.
但足够我扣留你24小时
Yeah, well, it's all I need to keep you here for 24 hours.
之后
And by then,
我会找到我要的证据
I will have my proof.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
他说得对  我们手上一无所有
He's right. We've got nothing.
一无所有太绝对了
"Nothing" is a strong word.
唯一能将汤姆与凶案联系起来的人就是凯尔
The only person that can link Tom to the killing is Kyle,
可他却什么也记不起来
and he doesn't remember anything.
而且要命的是
And on top of all of that,
证据显示是凯尔一人所为
the evidence shows that Kyle alone committed the murder.
听你这样说
Well, when you put it like that...
真有些凄凉
Yes, it sounds a little bleak.
或许就是这样
Maybe this is it,
每个凶案警察都怕遇见
what every homicide cop fears...
完美谋杀
the perfect murder.
这可不是完美谋杀
No. This is not the perfect murder.
-不可能  -有可能的
- Can't be. - It happens.
对我来说不可能  除非我写得出来
Not to me. Not unless I've written it.
我们漏掉些东西了
No, we're just missing something.
比如证据
Like proof.
在毫无证据的情况下  我们做了唯一能做的
Without it, we did the only thing we could.
和汤姆当面对峙  他眼都不眨一下
We went at Tom head-on. He didn't blink.
我们没辙了
We're out of moves.
还有一条路
We got one move left.
我们和汤姆正面交锋过了
We went at Tom head-on.
现在该暗地里较量了
Now we need to go at him sideways.
我想好该怎么做了
And I know just what to do.
格蕾塔  我理解你
Greta, I know how you feel.
你爱着汤姆
You're in love with Tom,
所以在你眼中只看得到他的好
and you want to see the best in him.
但你必须面对现实
But you have to look at the facts.
你说的不是真的
What you're saying isn't true.
好吗  都不是真的
Okay? None of it is.
好  那想想钱吧
Well, then take the money.
他怎么支付得起曼哈顿的公寓
How is he able to pay for an apartment in Manhattan?
我说过很多遍了  不是做毒贩
Not being a drug dealer, I'll tell you that much.
那这枚订婚戒指呢
What about that engagement ring?
他哪来钱买
How can he afford that?
他说这是他祖母留下的
He--he said it was his grandmother's.
格蕾塔  你是我最后的机会了
Greta, you are my last chance.
如果你不帮我
If you don't help me,
一个无辜的人将会因大卫的死
an innocent man is gonna go to prison for life
被判终身监禁
for David's murder.
不
No.
汤姆才是无辜的
Tom's the innocent one. Okay?
你已经抓到凶手了  跟我未婚夫无关
You got your killer, and it's not my fiance.
我还在等你们所谓的证据呢
I'm still waiting on that proof of yours.
还没找到吗
No?
什么都没找到
Nothing?
多谢款待
Well, thanks for the hospitality.
有可以填写的服务
Is there a comment card I could fill out
评价卡吗
about the level of service I received?
你可以走了
You're free to go.
见好就收
Take advantage while you can.
格蕾塔告诉我你们的谈话了
Yeah, Greta told me about your little conversation.
那就是你们的把戏吗
That was your big play,
利用我的未婚妻来对付我
to use my own fiancee against me?
她迟早会发现你的真面目的
She's gonna figure out who you are sooner or later,
你将如何应对呢
so what are you gonna do about it then?
凯尔·詹宁斯申请保释
Kyle Jennings made bail.
几小时前释放了
Got released a couple of hours ago.
等等  凯尔被放出去了
Wait. Kyle is out?
保释金要一百万美金  他哪来这么多钱
His bail was set at $1 million. Where'd he get the money?
他有个很有钱的叔叔
Turns out he's got an uncle who's got some serious dough.
如果我是你  我会避开他
I'd steer clear of him if I was you.
你跟他瞎掰了什么谎话
What kind of lies did you tell him?
我们什么都没说  但凯尔是个聪明人
We didn't tell him anything, but Kyle's a smart guy.
他会弄明白的
He's gonna do the math.
我要求警方保护
I want police protection.
我想你没干啥坏事
I thought you didn't do anything wrong.
我是没有  可多亏你们  凯尔以为我干了
I didn't, but thanks to you, Kyle thinks that I did,
现在他又被放出去
and now he's out there.
你们在知道他有可能会袭击我的情况下
Y-you're releasing me with knowledge and forethought
释放我
that he could attack me.
如果他真做了
If he does,
想想我会对你们提起的诉讼
think about the lawsuit I'll file against you.
埃斯波西托警探  请处理威廉姆斯先生释放的相关事宜
Detective Esposito, please process Mr. Williams
然后护送他回到他的公寓  确保安全
and then escort him to his apartment, make sure it's clear,
之后你就靠你自己了
and then after that, you are on your own.
我会在评价卡上在"优良服务"一项上
I'll be sure to check "Excellent Service"
画勾的
on that comment card.
我要在大楼外安排一辆巡逻车
I want a patrol car outside the building.
想都别想
Yeah, well, that's not gonna happen.
我会过来  让你...
I'm gonna come over and let you-- aah!
趴下  待在车里
Get down! Stay in the car.
纽约警局  放下棒子  举起手
NYPD! Drop that bat and show me your hands.
我知道你对我做了什么
I know what you did to me.
不  我没有
No, I didn't. I-I didn't.
你让我杀了人  现在我要杀了你
You made me kill a man and now I'm gonna do the same to you!
凯尔  不  求你  我...
Kyle, no, please. I...
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
你在说谎
You're lying.
不  我说的是真话
No, I am. I swear.
他要把格蕾塔从我身边抢走
He was gonna take Greta away from me.
我不得不采取行动
I had to do something.
抱歉我利用了你
I'm sorry I used you.
求你别
Just please don't...
别伤害我
Please don't-- don't hurt me.
好了  够了
Okay. Enough.
演得不错吧  我骗到你了
Good actor, huh? I had you going.
汤姆·威廉姆斯  你因谋杀大卫·洛克
Tom Williams, you are under arrest
而被捕
for the murder of David Lock.
等等
Wait. Hang on a second.
凯尔
Just--Kyle...
什么  凯尔
What--Kyle?
抱歉
Sorry.
凯尔来不了
Kyle couldn't make it.
但他...
But he, uh...
送来了他的问候
sends his regards.
转过去
Turn around.
我告诉你  兄弟
I'm gotta tell you, bro,
像你那样冲过来
You coming at me like that...
我差点都相信真有僵尸了
You almost made me a believer.
别闹了
Stop it.
别玩了
Don't do that.
怪吓人的
You're creeping me out.
你做得太棒了  凯尔
Ah, you really nailed it, Kyle.
你做的装扮是成功的关键
Your costume is what sold that bit.
通过帮助我们
Yeah, and by helping us,
你也帮了自己
you've actually helped yourself.
有了汤姆的认罪
The DA is looking into
地检官正在想办法
dismissing the charges against you
撤销对你的指控
now that he has Tom's confession.
探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective, Mr. Castle,
真不知道该怎么感谢你们
I-I don't know how to thank you--
这套僵尸装扮再借我一天
Uh, let me borrow the zombie outfit
就算感谢我了
for another day, we'll call it even.
你留着吧
You know what? Keep it.
我行尸走肉的日子到头了
My zombie walking days are over.
我希望忘掉这一切
I just... want to put all this behind me.
一个人怎么能把那种事忘却呢
How does somebody put something like that behind them?
他需要心理治疗
He's gonna need therapy.
那有帮助
It helps.
一开始他根本就无法接受
At first he won't even be able to deal with it.
即便是抬脚走路
It's gonna take everything that he's got
撑过一天的生活
to just put one foot in front of the other
都要耗费他全部的力量
and get through the day.
我不知道你在看心理医生
I didn't know you were seeing a therapist.
我不想找借口
Yeah, well, I didn't want to make any excuses.
我想花费时间
I just wanted to... put in the time
作出努力
and do the work.
但我想我快要找到自己的位置了
But I think I'm almost where I want to be now.
你的位置在哪儿
And... where is that?
一个能让我终于承受住那天
In a place where I can finally accept
发生的一切的地方
everything that happened that day.
一切
Everything.
我想
I think...
我懂
I understand.
我跟你提到的墙
And, um, that wall that I was telling you about...
我想它正在倒掉
I think it's coming down.
倒掉时  我希望能在场
Well, I'd like to be there when it does.
我也希望你在场
Yeah, I'd like you to be there, too.
-但是不花僵尸妆  -不知道
- Only without the zombie makeup. - I don't know.
僵尸妆挺适合你的  卡塞尔
I kind of think that the zombie makeup suits you, Castle.
那当然  我怎么打扮都帅
Yeah, I make it work.
明天见
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
胜利是我的
Victory is mine.
1,000...
分
points.
今天我行大运
And that is the icing
这不过是锦上添花
on the cake that has been my day.
这就完了
That's it?
都结束了
It's over?
什么  阿丽克西斯
What? Come on, Alexis.
这只是游戏
It's just a game.
从我五岁开始的游戏
A game we started when I was 5,
现在结束了
and it's over.
我会毕业  上大学
And I'm going to graduate, leave for college,
我们分隔两地
and I'll be there and you'll be here,
我们只能在圣诞节和暑假玩
and we can play at Christmas and during the summer,
但是跟以前不一样了  对吧
but... It won't be the same, will it?
是的
No.
但是事情总会改变的
But you know what? Things change.
改变是好事
And change is good.
我做不到
I can't do it.
做什么
Do what?
去那么远的地方
Go that far away.
我想那样做  可是不能那么远
I want to go away, but not that far.
我为此恨自己  因为我的座右铭是
And I hate myself for it, because my personal motto is,
做自己最害怕的事
"Do the thing that you fear the most,"
但是每次我要点申请牛津或是斯坦福
but every time I get ready to hit the send button
确认邮件的发送键时
on my acceptance to oxford or stanford, I...
我就浑身难受
I get all sick inside.
你要追随内心的想法
Well, you... Follow your heart.
那样永远不会错
Follow your heart, you can't go wrong.
我心里的想法是
And my heart is telling me...
去哥伦比亚大学
go to Columbia.
但是还有个问题  如果我去哥伦比亚
But here's the other thing-- if I do this,
你得保证别总来找我
you have to promise not to drop in on me.
如果我去哥伦比亚
If I do this,
你得给我空间
you have to give me my space.
你能做到吗
Do you think you can do that?
我想我可以郑重发誓我会
I think I can give a sincere and solemn oath
努力的
to try.
那就
Then...
三局两胜吧
best two out of three.
我跟你没完
This isn't over.